{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Because DNA is a highly charged polyanion, its stability to heat denaturation", "opta": "does not depend on hydrophobic interactions", "optb": "increases with increasing salt", "optc": "is independent of G - C content", "optd": "decreases with increasing salt", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The sugar in RNA is __________ , the sugar in DNA is __________", "opta": "deoxyribose, ribose", "optb": "ribose, deoxyribose", "optc": "ribose, phosphate", "optd": "ribose, uracil", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Nucleoside is a pyrimidine or purine base", "opta": "covalently bonded to a sugar", "optb": "ionically bonded to a sugar", "optc": "hydrogen bonded to a sugar", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In gel electrophoresis, what fragments will move most quickly through a gel?", "opta": "Large fragments", "optb": "Small fragments", "optc": "Large genome", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which pyrimidine base contains an amino group at carbon 4?", "opta": "Cytosine", "optb": "Thymine", "optc": "Uracil", "optd": "Adenine", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Nucleotide bases and aromatic amino acids absorb light respectively at", "opta": "280 and 260 nm", "optb": "260 and 280 nm", "optc": "270 and 280 nm", "optd": "260 and 270 nm", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The glycosidic bonds in DNA and RNA", "opta": "connect the sugar to the base", "optb": "can be hydrolyzed by OH- ion", "optc": "stabilize Watson-Crick H-bonds", "optd": "are free to rotate over about 180\u00b0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Nucleic acids can be analyzed experimentally by their", "opta": "molecular weight", "optb": "absorption of visible light", "optc": "absorption of uv light", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Thymidine", "opta": "can participate in hydrophobic interactions due to its methyl group", "optb": "is replaced by uracil in RNA", "optc": "normally forms two hydrogen bonds with adenosine", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A nucleotide consists of", "opta": "a sugar, a base and a phosphate", "optb": "a sugar and a phosphate", "optc": "paired bases", "optd": "a sugar, a base and three phosphates", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A five carbon sugar lacking a hydrogen at the number 2 carbon is found in", "opta": "DNA", "optb": "RNA", "optc": "mRNA", "optd": "rDNA", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The unfavourable free energy associated with not satisfying a hydrogen bond after formation of the double helix is approximately", "opta": "10 kJ/mol", "optb": "20 kJ/mol", "optc": "25 kJ/mol", "optd": "30 kJ/mol", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The most stabilizing force for nucleic acids is", "opta": "hydrogen bonds", "optb": "electrostatic bond", "optc": "Van der Waals", "optd": "conformational entropy", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A purine with an amine (NH2) group on the 6th carbon is", "opta": "adenine", "optb": "cytosine", "optc": "thymine", "optd": "guanine", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is found on RNA but not DNA?", "opta": "Uracil", "optb": "Deoxyribose", "optc": "Phosphate", "optd": "Adenine", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a purine?", "opta": "Cytosine", "optb": "Adenine", "optc": "Thymine", "optd": "Uracil", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}